Guide to the Allen R. Maxwell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Allen R. Maxwell papers
1875-2010
MS 2017
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
25
(93 boxes)
The papers document the professional career and research interests of anthropologist Allen R. Maxwell. The papers include correspondence, manuscripts of published works and drafts of unpublished works, grant applications, fieldnotes, research notes, subject files, photographic slides and audio recordings.
Maxwell, Allen R.
Biographical / Historical
Allen Richmond Maxwell, Jr. was born on December 10, 1939 in Hanover, New Hampshire. He attended the University of Michigan, where he received a B.A. degree in anthropology in 1961. The summer after his graduation he accompanied Michigan linguistics professor William J. Gedney, a specialist in Thai languages, to Thailand to serve as an instructor in an intensive Thai language course for Peace Corps volunteers. His experience with Peace Corps Training Program Thailand convinced him to pursue future anthropological fieldwork in Southeast Asia. He remained at the University of Michigan to pursue an M.A. degree in linguistics, which he received in 1962.
The following year, Maxwell applied to Yale University's M.A. program in Southeast Asian Studies, but was instead accepted by the department of anthropology, where he pursued a doctoral degree under the supervision of Professor Harold C. Conklin. Yale was designated as a center for the National Defense Foreign Language Title VI Indonesian program, and he obtained a fellowship for the study of Indonesian from 1962 through 1966. Initially interested in pursuing ethnographic field work in Indonesian Kalimantan, the country's volatile political climate in the mid-to-late 1960s led Maxwell to turn to neighboring Brunei. With the aid of a pre-doctoral fellowship from the Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research and a National Institutes of Health research grant, he pursued ethnographic and linguistic research focused on Brunei's Kadayan people from 1968 through 1971, spending most of his time in Kampung Psasaw-Pyasaw in the Labu Valley. Upon his return to Yale, he taught at Southern Connecticut State College, and later became an instructor at Barnard College in New York City in 1972. In 1974, he joined the Department of Anthropology at the University of Alabama, and remained there throughout his career. In 1980, Maxwell submitted a dissertation entitled "Urang Darat: An Ethnographic Study of the Kadayan of Labu Valley, Brunei," for which he received the Ph.D.
Maxwell's ethnographic work and writings on Brunei centered on Kadayan kinship, environment, social structure, and ethnohistory. His linguistic writings attended to the Brunei variety of Malay and its Kadayan sub-dialect. Of particular interest was his compilation and analysis of several versions of the Sya'ir Awang Simawn, an epic poem describing the founding of Brunei.
His broader interests in ethnohistory and greater Borneo led Maxwell to conduct nine months of research on oral traditions in Sarawak, a Malaysian state and Brunei's southern neighbor. This survey work, carried out in the mid-1980s, was supported by the Fulbright Southeast Asia Research Grant Program and analyzed oral traditions among the Malays, Kayans, Kenyahs, and other ethnicities in Sarawak. His collection of the Sarawak Malay text, Cetera Syekh Othman, is particularly noteworthy. Maxwell was interested in the role played by these texts in the intergenerational transmission of sociocultural beliefs and practices.
From 1999 to 2000, Maxwell returned to Brunei as a visiting professor in the department of sociology and anthropology at Universiti Brunei Darussalam. In 2006 he was a visiting professor at the Institute of the Malay World and Civilization at Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, and the following year he was a senior Visiting Research Fellow at the Institute of East Asian Studies at Universiti Malaysia Sarawak. He retired from the University of Alabama in 2010.
Scope and Contents
The papers document the professional career and research interests of anthropologist Allen R. Maxwell. The papers include correspondence, manuscripts of published works and drafts of unpublished works, grant applications, fieldnotes, research notes, subject files, photographic slides and audio recordings. Materials related to his career and teaching (Series I and III) include correspondence with colleagues, syllabi and lecture notes from Barnard College and the University of Alabama. The bulk of the papers consists of materials that document his research (Series II, and IV to VII), which centered most closely on questions of kinship, language, social structure, environment, and ethnohistory among the Kadayan people of Brunei, with later interests in the oral traditions of various Sarawakian groups and more general issues of kinship universals. Of particular note are the materials relating to his four years of linguistic and ethnographic research in Brunei and the Malaysian state of Sarawak. Maxwell's research ethnographic data includes fieldnotes, genealogies, and visual materials from Brunei and Sarawak, a lexicon of the Kadayan dialect of Brunei Malay, and compilations of the Malay texts Sya'ir Awang Simawn and Cetera Syekh Othman.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into seven series: I. Correspondence, 1965-2010. II. Research, 1875-2010. III. Teaching, 1945-2010. IV. Visual materials, 1913-2010. V. Audio recordings, 1968-1989. VI. Malay lexicon and fieldnote cards, 1968-1988. VII. Computer disks 1968-2010.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Southeast Asia Collection Curator, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials in Series I-VI are open for research. Computer disks, Series VII are closed until processed.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Anthropology -- Research; Anthropology -- Brunei; Anthropology -- Malaysia; Ethnohistory -- Malaysia -- Sarawak; Kedayan (Bornean people); Brunei; Malaysia; Sarawak (Malaysia); Maxwell, Allen R.; University of Alabama
- Correspondence, 1965-2010; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically and includes letters to and from Maxwell regarding Ph.D. fieldwork in Brunei, later research fieldwork in Sarawak, job applications, grant proposals, conference papers, and more general correspondence with colleagues about the state of anthropology.
  - Conklin, Harold, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Maxwell, Allen (outgoing), 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Harrison, Tom, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brunei fieldwork, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Family, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Conklin, Harold, 1968-1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Donald, 1968-2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Yale University Library, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Job applications, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Grant proposals and manuscript submission, 1979-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Harold Conklin's festschrift, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sarawak fieldwork, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sarawak post-fieldwork, 1985-1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ATMA position at Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Research, 1875-circa 2010; Series II
  This series includes materials related the geographical areas where Maxwell carried out his fieldwork, namely Brunei and the Malaysian state of Sarawak. Materials related to these areas focus on Maxwell's studies of language, kinship, ethnohistory, and the environment in each. The series also includes writings on anthropological theory, framed with reference to ethnographic questions Maxwell pursued in the field. language, kinship, ethnohistory, and the environment. Lastly, the series includes grant applications completed by Maxwell to fund his fieldwork.
  - Brunei
    - Dissertation: Urang Darat, An Ethnographic, Study of the Kadayan of Labu Valley, Brunei
      - Dissertation: "Urang Darat, An Ethnographic Study of the Kadayan of Labu Valley, Brunei", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
      - Handwritten dissertation notes, 1967-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Kinship and genealogies
      - "Kadayan Malay Kin Terms and the Malay Language", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kadayan kin terminology, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - "The Language of Kadayan Kinship", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - "Kadayan Personal Names and Naming", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - "The Semantics of Basic Kadayan Kin Terms", 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - "Polysemy: Kin Terms, Taxonomy, and Synonymy", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Genealogically mapped denotata of Kadayan kin terms, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Kadayan marriage, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - "Genealogy of the Sultans of Brunei", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Genealogical relationships between heads of households in Kampung Pyasaw-Pyasaw, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - "Genealogical Networking and Ethnicity in Borneo", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Lexicon of Kadayan core kin terms, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - "The Brunei Salasilah: An Underexplored Genre of Southeast Asian Historical Texts", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - "The Silahsilah: History and Social Structure in the Brunei Ritual State", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - "The Story of the Late Syaikh 'Uthman", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - "Kadayan Kin Terms and Kin Classification", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - "Kadayan Residence: Rule, Structure, and Ethnicity", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "Kadayan Men and Women", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - "The Brunei Malay Kinship Terminological System", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Kadayan extension rules, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - "Competence and Performance in the Study of Kinship Terminology: Kinship Terminology and Distinctions of Language", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - A structural analysis of ethnicity and status in Brunei, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Marriages in Kampung Piasawpiasaw, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Brunei royal genealogies, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Kadayan kinship genealogies, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - "Folk Classification and Kadayan Kinship", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Patterns of social structure and behavior, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Kinship research notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
    - Language and linguistics
      - "Brunei Malay Phonology", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - "Phonology of Brunei Malay: a Phonemic Analysis by Minimal Pairs", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - "Lexemes and Derivation: The Kadayan (Malay) Case", 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Kinship diagrams and research notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - "Lexical Borrowing and Cultural Influence in Brunei Malay", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
      - "Lexical Data and Freudian Symbolism", 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - "Phonological Structure and Lexical Borrowing in Brunei Malay", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "English Loans in Brunei Malay", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Writings on Kadayan lexicon and phonology, circa 1968 - circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Merging vocabularies with "sort blocks by fields", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - "Assessing the Etymologies of the Ethnonym 'Kadayan'", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Preliminary note on language and orthography, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - "Prename Designators in Brunei Malay", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Structure of a titled name, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Ethnolinguistic map of the Brunei Bay, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Logical relationships pertaining between semantic dimensions and their features, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - An analysis of linguistic similarities between modern Brunei Malay, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Malay landscape and nature vocabulary, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Brunei Malay wordlists, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
      - Word medial 'h' in Brunei Malay, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Kadayan and Icelandic terms of directional orientation, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Malay wordlists, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
      - Swadesh lists, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Lexico-statistic list, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Transcripts for audio-cassettes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Linguistic research notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
      - Malay Swadesh lists, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
      - Brunei phoneme combinations, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Outline of Kadayan phonology and research notes, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Phonetics research notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Jawi transliterations, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - The designation 'General Brunei Malay', Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Notes on Bahasa Istiadat di-Raya, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Environment
      - "Erosion as an Unnatural Act: Universals and Ethnographic Explanation", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - A preliminary Kedayan ethnoornithology, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "River Names and Ethnicity in Brunei Darussalam", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - "The Local Classification of Rice Agricultural Subsistence Production in a Kadayan Village", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - "Polysemy and River-Name Ethnonymy in Brunei Darussalam: A Model for Understanding Ethnic Labeling in Borneo", circa 1968 - circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Incomplete manuscript on directional orientation, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Research notes on Kadayan directional orientation, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Incomplete manuscript on Kadayan orientation, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - "Environmentalism Beyond the Sierra Club: Indigenous Conceptions of Conservation in Borneo", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Brunei forestry and timber data, 1946-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Research notes on Kadayan rice cultivation, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - "Semantic Classification and Kadayan Agricultural Systems", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Research notes on Kadayan foods, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Notes on Kadayan fishing and rice cultivation, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Land utilization and tenure in Brunei, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Notes on Kadayan agriculture, hunting, and gathering, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Structure of a Kadayan rice field plot, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Data on Brunei export duties (non-jungle produce), 1881-1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Brunei, Sarawak, and Sabah mapping notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Sketches of Brunei river systems, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Personal and toponymic considerations in Kadayan naming, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Rainfall data for Labu Estate, Brunei, 1936-1974 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Ethnohistory
      - "The Death of a Historical Legacy: The Brunei Royal Family and a Problem of Generations", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - "Conversion to Islam in Brunei Darussalam; or, How did Brunei Come to be Muslim in the First Place?", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - "Nineteenth Century Brunei Before James Brooke", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Twentieth century census data on Brunei, 1906-1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - "Kadayan Ethnotoponymy as Ethnohistory", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Research notes on changes in Brunei Adat, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - "Malay Adat: Legal Concept or Colonial Artifice?", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Brunei demography, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Succession conflicts in the dynasty of Brunei, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - "The Relevance of Brunei Traditional Texts for Sarawak and Kalimantan Ethnohistory", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - "Prasasti-Prasasti Melayu Kuno", 1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - A Brunei letter to Manila, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - "Kedayan in the Shair Ken Tambuhan and Kadayan in Brunei", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Kadayans are not Malays, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Outline notes on the history of Labu, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - The devil is in the details: false consciousness and the invention of Brunei tradition(s), Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Headtaking manuscripts, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Is Tradition Always Being Reinvented? The Case of Brunei Darussalam", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - "Islam and the Religious History of Brunei", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Research notes on Brunei's connection with the Malay world, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - "A Problem in the Chronology of Brunei: When Did Sultan Hasan Reign?", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - "Kadayan Senses of their Past", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - "Human Origins Around Brunei Bay: A Fifth Division Jawi Account", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - "Historical Dictionary of Brunei Darussalam", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 10, Folder 8-11)
      - "Historical Dictionary of Brunei Darussalam", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
      - "The Place of the Kadayan in Traditional Brunei Society", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Old Malay inscriptions, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Jawi transliterations, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - "'Alamat Zaman Katahta'an Dinagri Brunai", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Sya'ir Awang Simawn
      - "What is the Sya'ir Awang Simawn?", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn version "A", 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn version "B", 1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn version "C", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn version "D", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn version "E", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn version "Z", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn collation, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn outlines and contents, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Textual analysis of the Sya'ir Awang Simawn, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn episodes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn "Kadayan" verses, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - "Phonological Intrusion and 'r' in Brunei Malay Oral Tradition: Prothesis, Anaptyxis, and Paragoge in a Rendition of the Brunei Malay Epic Sya'ir Awang Simawn", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Background information to the Sya'ir Awang Simawn, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - "Some Problems in Preserving Critical Ethnohistorical Oral Traditions: Working with Different Versions of the Brunei Malay Sya'ir Awang Simaun", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - "Assessing the Epic Status of the Brunei Malay Sya'ir Awang Simawn", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - "Exploring the Brunei Malay Epic the Sya'ir Awang Simawn", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - "What is the Sya'ir Awang Simawn?", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - "Headtaking and the Consolidation of Political Power in the Early Brunei State", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - "Exploring the Brunei Malay Epic the Sya'ir Awang Simawn", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - "The Oral Tradition Character of the Brunei Malay Sya'ir Awang Simawn", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - "Understanding an Epic: a Methodology for Collating the Sya'ir Awang Ismawn", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - "Morality in Old Brunei: The Language of Homage and Status in the Sya'ir Awang Simawn", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Toponymic data from the Sya'ir Awang Simawn, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Information on Awang Simawn- field notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - "Who is Awang Simawn?", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Awang Halak Awang Semaun Si-Jarambak, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Sya'ir Awang Simawn research notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Fieldbooks
      - Brunei field notes, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Kadayan language research notes, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Brunei gravestone transcriptions, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Brunei Jawi transcription, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
      - Jawi romanization, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Brunei excerpts, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
      - Brunei excerpts, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Brunei and Kadayan excerpts from older sources, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Malay poetry, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Kadayan and Limbang conversions, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Shair Dagang and Penyalin Shair Jawi inscriptions, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Brunei field journal, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Notes on slavery, forced trade, and feudal rights of nobles, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - A classification of the peoples of Sarawak, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Brunei Swadesh lists, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Brunei Swadesh lists, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Malay word list, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 19, Folder 2-5)
      - Compilation of Bruneian names, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Brunei place names, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Local Brunei names for plants, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Color-coded key for Brunei lexicon index cards, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - General
      - "List of Distinctions Characterizing a Kadayan Lifestyle", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - "Why the Kadayan Are Not Peasants", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Notes on a Kadayan style of living, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - "The Place of the Kadayan in Traditional Brunei Society", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - "Kadayan Ideas of Time", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - "The Kadayan and the Barunay", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 20, Folder 6)